Aman Bhuiyan

E: aub204@yahoo.com

M: 074 5041 3638

Website: https://amanbhuiyan.github.io/

London, United Kingdom

I am an experienced, and passionate .Net developer, with skills of SharePoint / BI / Microsoft Dynamics CRM. I am a cloud focus Devops, and have skills in cloud DeVops tools and platform. My background is from Information Technology. I have BSc (CSE) & MSc degree in IT. I am problem solver with can do attitude. I can take responsibilities and enjoy learning new things.

Technical skills:

Framework ASP.Net Core, ASP.net MVC, WPF, entity Framework

Programming Languages: C#, python

Database / BI: SQL Server , Power BI , Microsoft Access, SSIS, SSRS,

SSAS, Data Warehouse, Scripts, Schema, Querying

AWS: AWS Lambda, AWS cloud platform, AWS services, EC2,

S3, RDS, Dynamodb, Cloudformation, Cloudwatch, VPC,

ELB, EFS, Route53, Cloudfront, CI/CD Pipeline,

Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible.

Azure: Microsoft Azure (Compute, Storage, Networking),

Azure Virtual machines, containers, Storage account, Azure function, ARM, Virtual Network,

CI/CD

SharePoint experience SharePoint 2010, 2013, SharePoint designer,

Office365, SharePoint online, Windows Azure

Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

Development tools: Visual studio 2008, 2010, 2013, 2015, 2019 Visual web

developer Net beans,

S/W development methodologies: Agile, TDD, SCRUM

S/W testing: Unit testing, Nunit, System testing, Seleinium

Version Control: TFS, Git , Github

Professional Experience:

1. IT Analyst (SharePoint / .Net developer)-Consultant

London borough of Merton, London,

July 2019 - Continue

Responsibilities:

- Analysing systems, finding program needs, consulting with users, getting clients requirements, documenting technical specifications.
- Creating applications using, ASP.Net core, C# and Sql servers, Entity framework,
 HTML5, React js, LINQ query, Entity framework, SharePoint etc.
- Managing & deploying systems in development, test and production environment
- Client engagement & managing excellent BAU experience.
- 2. Senior Developer (Consultant)

London borough of Lewisham, London, May 2019 - July 2019

Responsibilities:

- Creating application using, ASP.Net Core, MVC, Web api, C# and Sql servers, Entity framework, React Js, LINQ query etc.
- I have developed a "Data breach management system" using **C#**, SQL Server, ASP .net core, Html, CSS, JavaScript, SharePoint.
- Overall Responsibilities for developing solution on the organisation
- Using Microsoft SQL Server, ASP.net, C#, Microsoft InfoPath Designer, SharePoint
 Designer, MVC etc
- Using front end technologies html, css, angular js, javascript, jquery, bootstrap

3. Systems Developer - Consultant (Development)

Shoosmiths LLP, Northampton - Dec 2017- February 2019,

Responsibilities:

Systems Development and Administration

- Design, develop and maintain key software components using, C#, Microsoft SQL Server ,and Microsoft SharePoint Server in accordance with organisation's Software and Security Development Lifecycles.
- Implement Business workflows and solutions for business process automation.
- Release of software version to UAT and production.
- Creating bespoke application using C# and Sql servers, Entity framework,
 Angula js, linq query etc.
- Ensure systems change management is carried out in accordance with agreed standards and procedures.

4. SharePoint Developer [SharePoint / .Net]

Ince & Co LLP - July 2016 - Dec 2017,

London

Responsibilities:

- Analysing systems, finding program needs, consulting with users, getting clients requirements, documenting technical specifications.
- Creating Web parts, Application pages, event recievers using ASP.Net, SharePoint, C#, and SQL Servers.
- Remodelling and re-structuring old classic asp application to brand new application using new technology **ASP.Net Core, ASP.net MVC**.
- Creating bespoke application using, ASP.Net MVC, C# and Sql servers, Entity framework, Angula js, linq query etc.
 - Managing systems in **development**, **test and production** environment
- Deploy developed and tested solutions from dev to test or production environment

- Debugging, testing, modifying and correcting errors of existing system and updating whenever necessary.
 - Creating interactive user interface using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery.
- Updating Solutions, creating new solutions **Web parts, Application pages**, event receivers, timer jobs, deploy in dev environment, test environment and then in live environment upon successful testing.
- Writing Technical, documentation, user documentation and business process for IT Systems.
 - 5. Systems Developer [SharePoint / BI]

January - June, 2016

Building Research Establishment, London

Responsibilities:

- I was involved on setting up and configuring SharePoint environment. I have created three tiers SharePoint farm on windows Hyper V.
- Develop and maintain code written in C#, asp.net, sql server and SharePoint
- Created complex SSRS report from SharePoint, SQL Server, Data warehouse, data mart.
- Maintained and supported **application**, **visual studio custom solution**.
- Creating new feature or adding features in existing system using asp.net, C#, sql server etc.
- 6. Systems Developer [SSRS BI / SharePoint]

April 2015 - Aug-2015

Capita IT Enterprise Services & NHS- Central London Community Health Care NHS Trust

London

Responsibilities:

• I was involved in taking leadership of developing **SharePoint/.Net** systems, and managed business process for **SharePoint e-forms** for different department of client.

- Administering SharePoint farm / environment, developing and maintaining SharePoint workflows, list, libraries, forms, features / solutions.
- Created SharePoint BI reports, SSRS projects, SSIS packages and ETL / data warehouse. I had researched and got skills on K2 workflow, smart object, Smartforms, view etc.
- I have successfully delivered a SharePoint/.Net project for NHS CLCH, Learning & Development team to manage their external training. I used Microsoft SharePoint 2010, Sharepoint Workflows, InfoPath designer 2010, SQL server 2008, C#, HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript.
- I have developed SSRS reports for Electronic appraisal team, from Microsoft SharePoint Electronic appraisal system. Electronic appraisal system is an existing SharePoint product, I was responsible to extract the data into SQL server and prepare user friendly reports for directorates. User wanted to find out how appraise are performing in each directorate on different categories. I have used Microsoft SQL Server 2012, Visual Studio 2013, SQL Server reporting Service project (SSRS).
- I have taken lead part in resolving 3rd line Support for any SharePoint /.Net issues. Actively involved on looking after service desk calls related with SharePoint/.Net product. Resolved and reduced the number of calls which were appreciated by head of development and innovation team.
- Apart from these I have developed and supported numerous SharePoint product, record management systems, and actively used SharePoint, InfoPath, SharePoint designer, C#, VB.Net, SQL Server 2008, 2012, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- 7. Systems Developer (.Net & Sharepoint) April 2013 to April 2015

The Royal Liverpool & Broadgreen University Hospital NHS Trust

Responsibilities:

- Dynamic CRM Customization
- Creating bespoke application using, ASP.Net MVC, C# and Sql servers, Entity framework, Angula js, linq query etc.
- I have developed a SharePoint product for technical support team to capture new user IT request. Before they were using fax service for this request. After developing the system TS team could respond to the request quite quick. I have used **SharePoint 2010**, **C#**, **ASP.Net**, **SQL Server**, **HTML**, **CSS**, and **JavaScript**.

- Overall Responsibilities for developing SharePoint solution on the organisation
- Branding SharePoint site, creating web parts, application pages, event receivers, farm and sandbox solutions, dealing with large data
- Using Microsoft SharePoint 2010, Microsoft SQL Server, ASP.net, C#, Microsoft
 InfoPath Designer, SharePoint Designer, MVC etc
- Using front end technologies html, css, angular js, javascript, jquery, bootstrap

6. Web developer / Freelancer

June, 2011- April 2013

- Building website and web application from scratch
- Creating .Net application
- Making professional website using CMS, Wordpress, Joomla
- Skills of Sharepoint EDMS, Sharepoint ECM, Record management
- Developing, Managing, maintaining of websites, using cms, (joomla, wordpress,) and in asp.net
- Using C#, SQL server, ASP.net, mentoring C#, SQL Server,
- Using SQL server reporting services
- Using software development lifecycle and documentation skills

Training Course attended:

Course title	Training provider	Duration	Year
			completed
K2 Workflow, K2 SmartObjet, and Smart form	K2, UK	5 days	2016
Windows Azure Mobile Services (A Lap around)	Microsoft	1	2013
Developer feature in windows 8	Microsoft	1	2013
SharePoint-Advanced workflow in SP Designer	Combined Knowledge	1	2014

Education:

1. MSc in Information Technology

University of East London London, UK, Nov, 2009- March, 2011. **3 distinctions, 4 credits out of 8 courses**

2. BSC: Computer Science and Engineering

Jahangiragar University
Dhaka, Bangladesh, 2000-2005, 1st Class

References: Available on request.